Guide to the Cass Gilbert Papers and Architectural Drawings 1883-1952 (Bulk 1900-1934) PR 21
New-York Historical Society
Cass Gilbert papers and architectural drawings
1883-1952
New-York Historical Society
Gilbert, Cass, 1859-1934
PR 21
380 Linear feet (696 boxes, 444 bound volumes)
The Cass Gilbert Collection contains the professional and personal papers of the architect Cass Gilbert. This includes information on his architectural projects, professional affliations, and personal business.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Cass Gilbert Jr. and Emily Gilbert, 1956 and 1957.
Access Restrictions
Open to qualified researchers. Materials are stored offsite and advance notice is required for use. Please contact printroom@nyhistory.org prior to your research visit to coordinate access. Keep in mind that it will take between two (2) and five (5) business days for collections to arrive, and you should plan your research accordingly.
Biographical Note
Cass Gilbert was born on November 24, 1859 in Zanesville, Ohio to Samuel Augustus Gilbert and Elizabeth Fulton Wheeler Gilbert. The family moved to St. Paul Minnesota in 1868, and in 1878 Gilbert went to study architecture at Massachusetts Institute of Technology. After traveling and studying in Europe, he joined the New York office of McKim, Mead & White in 1880. In 1882, he was sent to St. Paul to open a branch office for McKim, Mead & White and to oversee the building of depots, terminals, and hotels for the Northern Pacific Railroad. Within two years, the office collapsed and Gilbert formed a partnership with James Knox Taylor in St. Paul that lasted until 1892. Gilbert produced churches and houses in Minnesota and was a recognized architect when he won a competition to design the Minnesota State Capitol in 1895.
In 1899, Gilbert returned to New York City and received a number of significant commissions. He won a competition to design the United States Custom House (1901-1907) and designed the 24 storied building at 90 West Street (1905-1907) in Manhattan. From 1911-1913, Gilbert worked on the Woolworth Building. At 55 stories tall, it was the tallest building in the world from 1913 to 1930 and became one of Gilbert's most famous designs. Other buildings in New York designed by Gilbert include the New York Life Insurance Company Building (1925-1928) and the US Courthouse (1936), which was completed after his death. Gilbert also completed designs for the George Washington Memorial Bridge (1927-1931) that proved to be too expensive and were never used.
Gilbert also became known for his work on the Art Building in the Louisiana Purchase Exposition in 1904 which eventually became the St. Louis Art Museum. He also designed the St. Louis Public Library (1907-1912) and the Detroit Public Library (1913-1921). His work in Washington D.C. included the US Treasury Annex (1918-1919), the US Chamber of Commerce (1924-1925), and the US Supreme Court Building (1933-1935).
Gilbert was active in art and architectural organizations. He was appointed by President Theodore Roosevelt as chairman of the Council of Fine Arts. He was made a member of the Commission of Fine Arts by President Taft and reappointed to the post by President Woodrow Wilson. He was a long time member of the American Institute of Architects and served as its president from 1908-1909. In 1919 he resigned his membership from the AIA after disputes with the leadership of the organization. He was also a long time member of the National Academy of Design and served as its president from 1926-1932. He also served as a member of the National Institute of Arts and Letters.
Gilbert was recognized in America and abroad for his architectural work. He received honorary degrees from the University of Michigan, Oberlin College, and Middlebury College and was awarded the Society of Art and Sciences Gold Medal Award in 1930. In Europe, he was made an honorary member of the Agricultural Society of the University of Liverpool and an honorary foreign member of the Royal Academy of Arts. He was also decorated with the French Legion of Honor.
In 1887, Gilbert married Julia Tappan Finch, the daughter of a wealthy attorney from Milwaukee. Together they had three children: Cass Gilbert Jr., Emily Finch, and Julia Swift who became the wife of Charles Morgan Post. The family owned many properties including places in Manhattan and Connecticut. Gilbert was active in various social clubs including the Century Club and the Union Club. Gilbert died on vacation in Brockenhurst, England in 1934 at the age of 75. Cass Gilbert Jr. worked as an architect in his father's office and finished many of the office's projects after his death.
Scope and Content Note
The Cass Gilbert Collection spans the period from 1883-1952 (bulk 1900-1934) and contains professional and personal papers relating to the architect Cass Gilbert. Most of this collection consists of files related to his numerous architectural projects. These files contain materials related to projects that he completed as well as projects that he worked on but did not complete. The collection also documents his extensive work in art and architectural associations. His personal papers mainly relate to personal business and some family letters are included. The arrangement attempts to adhere to Gilbert's filing system as closely as possible. The finding aid includes reference to Gilbert's architectural drawings; more detailed listings of drawings are available from the N-YHS Reference Librarian.
Arrangement
The collection is divided into nine series:
Series I: Project Files
Series II: Office Files
Series III: Professional Organizations
Series IV: Personal Files
Series V: Lantern Slides
Series VI: Record Book of Drawings
Series VII: Scrapbooks
Series VIII: Metal Printing Plates
Series IX: European Sketchbooks
Series X: Architectural Drawings
Related Material at the Department of Prints, Photographs, and Architectural Collections
Photographs of many Cass Gilbert projects can be found in the Geographic File, PR20. A photograph of the dinner thrown by F.W. Woolworth in Cass Gilbert's honor can be found in the Portrait File, PR52, under Groups, Commercial, in Large Format. There is also a photograph of Cass Gilbert and his family in the Portrait File, PR 52, under "G" in Medium Format.
Agreements; Architecture -- United States -- 19th century.; Architectural records.; Bids.; Brochures.; Buildings -- Connecticut.; Buildings -- Minnesota.; Buildings -- New Jersey.; Buildings -- New York (State); Cashbooks.; Clippings (information artifacts); Commercial buildings -- United States.; Contracts.; Correspondence.; Drawings (visual works); Dwellings -- United States.; Financial statements.; Floor plans.; Historic buildings -- United States.; Lantern slides.; Ledgers (account books); Letter books.; Memorandums.; New York (N.Y.) -- Buildings, structures, etc.; Notes (documents); Office buildings -- United States.; Payroll records.; Photographs.; Printing plates.; Public buildings -- United States.; Railroad stations -- United States.; Reports.; Renderings (drawings); Scrapbooks.; Sketches.; Sketchbooks.; Skyscrapers -- United States.; Specifications.; Washington (D.C.) -- Buildings, structures, etc.; Alexander Hamilton United States Custom House (New York, N.Y.); American Institute of Architects; Aus, Gunvald; Blashfield, Edwin Howland, 1848-1936; Burr, Stiles; Chamber of Commerce of the United States of America; Comstock, Louis K. (Louis Kossuth), 1865-1962; Detroit Public Library; French, Daniel Chester, 1850-1931; George A. Fuller Company; Gilbert, Charles; Gilbert, Julia Finch, 1862-1952; Gilbert, Samuel; Hedden Construction Co.; James Stewart and Company; Minnesota State Capitol (Saint Paul, Minn.: 1883-1905); New York Insurance Company Building; Olmstead, F. H.; Rockart, John R., approximately 1872-1951; St. Louis Art Museum; Thompson-Starrett Co.; United States. Commission of Fine Arts; United States. Department of the Treasury -- Buildings.; United States. Supreme Court -- Buildings -- Washington (D.C.); Webb, Aston, Sir, 1849-1930; West Street Building (New York, N.Y.); Woolworth Building (New York, N.Y.)
- Series I. Project Files
  Scope and Contents note
  This series includes material related to Cass Gilbert's architectural projects. Most of the projects are buildings built by Gilbert. However the files also include information on projects he competed for but did not receive or are documents regarding a particular subject or a business. This series represents the bulk of the collection.
  - Subseries I: Foldered Material
    This subseries contains the box and foldered material regarding Cass Gilbert projects. The material has been filed alphabetically by project and then by the project number assigned by Gilbert's office. Gilbert also designated material within the project files by type. Thus, the project files are also divided by type of material. The types of material include Preliminary Correspondence, Correspondence, Memoranda/Notes, Specifications, Bid Documents, Proposals, Reports, Contracts/Agreements, Financial Statements (includes Requisitions), Change Orders, Drawings, Photographs, etc.
    - Abbott Apartment Building (Milwaukee, WI), 1890 (Offsite-box 1)
    - Adams Stable (112 East 52nd Street, NY, NY), 1900-1910 (Offsite-box 1)
    - American Academy of Arts and Letters (New York, NY) (Box 1 of 5), 1928-1934 (Offsite-box 1)
    - American Academy of Arts and Letters (New York, NY) (Box 2 of 5), 1928-1934 (Offsite-box 2)
    - American Academy of Arts and Letters (New York, NY) (Box 3 of 5), 1928-1934 (Offsite-box 3)
    - American Academy of Arts and Letters (New York, NY) (Box 4 of 5), 1928-1934 (Offsite-box 4)
    - American Academy of Arts and Letters (New York, NY) (Box 5 of 5), 1928-1934 (Offsite-box 5)
    - American Insurance Company Building (Newark, NJ) (Box 1 of 8), 1902-1930 (Offsite-box 5)
    - American Insurance Company Building (Newark, NJ) (Box 2 of 8), 1902-1930 (Offsite-box 6)
    - American Insurance Company Building (Newark, NJ) (Box 3 of 8), 1902-1930 (Offsite-box 7)
    - American Insurance Company Building (Newark, NJ) (Box 4 of 8), 1902-1930 (Offsite-box 8)
    - American Insurance Company Building (Newark, NJ) (Box 5 of 8), 1902-1930 (Offsite-box 9)
    - American Insurance Company Building (Newark, NJ) (Box 6 of 8), 1902-1930 (Offsite-box 10)
    - American Insurance Company Building (Newark, NJ) (Box 7 of 8), 1902-1930 (Offsite-box 11)
    - American Insurance Company Building (Newark, NJ) (Box 8 of 8), 1902-1930 (Offsite-box 12)
    - American Terra Cotta and Ceramic Company, 1901 (Offsite-box 12)
    - Arkansas State Capitol (Little Rock, AR) (Box 1 of 13), 1901-1930 (Offsite-box 13)
    - Arkansas State Capitol (Little Rock, AR) (Box 2 of 13), 1901-1930 (Offsite-box 14)
    - Arkansas State Capitol (Little Rock, AR) (Box 3 of 13), 1901-1930 (Offsite-box 15)
    - Arkansas State Capitol (Little Rock, AR) (Box 4 of 13), 1901-1930 (Offsite-box 16)
    - Arkansas State Capitol (Little Rock, AR) (Box 5 of 13), 1901-1930 (Offsite-box 17)
    - Arkansas State Capitol (Little Rock, AR) (Box 6 of 13), 1901-1930 (Offsite-box 18)
    - Arkansas State Capitol (Little Rock, AR) (Box 7 of 13), 1901-1930 (Offsite-box 19)
    - Arkansas State Capitol (Little Rock, AR) (Box 8 of 13), 1901-1930 (Offsite-box 20)
    - Arkansas State Capitol (Little Rock, AR) (Box 9 of 13), 1901-1930 (Offsite-box 21)
    - Arkansas State Capitol (Little Rock, AR) (Box 10 of 13), 1901-1930 (Offsite-box 22)
    - Arkansas State Capitol (Little Rock, AR) (Box 11 of 13), 1901-1930 (Offsite-box 23)
    - Arkansas State Capitol (Little Rock, AR) (Box 12 of 13), 1901-1930 (Offsite-box 24)
    - Arkansas State Capitol (Little Rock, AR) (Box 13 of 13), 1901-1930 (Offsite-box 25)
    - Atlantic Refining Company (Philadelphia, PA) (Box 1 of 5), 1919-1920 (Offsite-box 26)
    - Atlantic Refining Company (Philadelphia, PA) (Box 2 of 5), 1919-1920 (Offsite-box 27)
    - Atlantic Refining Company (Philadelphia, PA) (Box 3 of 5), 1919-1920 (Offsite-box 28)
    - Atlantic Refining Company (Philadelphia, PA) (Box 4 of 5), 1919-1920 (Offsite-box 29)
    - Atlantic Refining Company (Philadelphia, PA) (Box 5 of 5), 1919-1920 (Offsite-box 30)
    - Austin Nichols & Company (Brooklyn, NY) (Box 1 of 13), 1913-1930 (Offsite-box 30)
    - Austin Nichols & Company (Brooklyn, NY) (Box 2 of 13), 1913-1930 (Offsite-box 31)
    - Austin Nichols & Company (Brooklyn, NY) (Box 3 of 13), 1913-1930 (Offsite-box 32)
    - Austin Nichols & Company (Brooklyn, NY) (Box 4 of 13), 1913-1930 (Offsite-box 33)
    - Austin Nichols & Company (Brooklyn, NY) (Box 5 of 13), 1913-1930 (Offsite-box 34)
    - Austin Nichols & Company (Brooklyn, NY) (Box 6 of 13), 1913-1930 (Offsite-box 35)
    - Austin Nichols & Company (Brooklyn, NY) (Box 7 of 13), 1913-1930 (Offsite-box 36)
    - Austin Nichols & Company (Brooklyn, NY) (Box 8 of 13), 1913-1930 (Offsite-box 37)
    - Austin Nichols & Company (Brooklyn, NY) (Box 9 of 13), 1913-1930 (Offsite-box 38)
    - Austin Nichols & Company (Brooklyn, NY) (Box 10 of 13), 1913-1930 (Offsite-box 39)
    - Austin Nichols & Company (Brooklyn, NY) (Box 11 of 13), 1913-1930 (Offsite-box 40)
    - Austin Nichols & Company (Brooklyn, NY) (Box 12 of 13), 1913-1930 (Offsite-box 41)
    - Austin Nichols & Company (Brooklyn, NY) (Box 13 of 13), 1913-1930 (Offsite-box 42)
    - Peter Bent Brigham Hospital, 1910 (Offsite-box 42)
    - Beverly Public Library (Beverley, MA) (Box 1 of 3), 1905-1919 (Offsite-box 42)
    - Beverly Public Library (Beverley, MA) (Box 2 of 3), 1905-1919 (Offsite-box 43)
    - Beverly Public Library (Beverley, MA) (Box 3 of 3), 1905-1919 (Offsite-box 44)
    - Brazer Building (Boston, MA), 1896, 1901 (Offsite-box 44)
    - Bridgeport Savings Bank (Bridgeport, CT) (Box 1 of 6), 1914-1934 (Offsite-box 45)
    - Bridgeport Savings Bank (Bridgeport, CT) (Box 2 of 6), 1914-1934 (Offsite-box 46)
    - Bridgeport Savings Bank (Bridgeport, CT) (Box 3 of 6), 1914-1934 (Offsite-box 47)
    - Bridgeport Savings Bank (Bridgeport, CT) (Box 4 of 6), 1914-1934 (Offsite-box 48)
    - Bridgeport Savings Bank (Bridgeport, CT) (Box 5 of 6), 1914-1934 (Offsite-box 49)
    - Bridgeport Savings Bank (Bridgeport, CT) (Box 6 of 6), 1914-1934 (Offsite-box 50)
    - E.C. Bridgman (Publisher and Mounter), 1901-1902 (Offsite-box 50)
    - Broad Street Property Development (New York, NY), 1902 (Offsite-box 50)
    - Broadway Chambers Building (New York, NY) (Box 1 of 3), 1899-1926 (Offsite-box 51)
    - Broadway Chambers Building (New York, NY) (Box 2 of 3), 1899-1926 (Offsite-box 52)
    - Broadway Chambers Building (New York, NY) (Box 3 of 3), 1899-1926 (Offsite-box 53)
    - Brooklyn Army Terminal (see United States Army Supply Base)
    - Brooklyn Rapid Transit, 1903 (Offsite-box 53)
    - Brunswick School (Greenwich, CT), 1933 (Offsite-box 53)
    - Bureau of the American Republics (Washington, DC), 1903 (Offsite-box 53)
    - Burnham & Co. Architects, 1903-1904 (Offsite-box 53)
    - Alexander Sterling Calder, 1904 (Offsite-box 54)
    - Camden County Building Committee (Camden, NJ), 1902-1903 (Offsite-box 54)
    - Capitol Building (Havana, Cuba), 1903-1904 (Offsite-box 54)
    - Capitol Improvement Commission (Madison, WI), 1903-1904 (Offsite-box 54)
    - Carnegie Library (St. Paul, MN), 1903 (Offsite-box 54)
    - Carpenters' Letters, 1901-1902 (Offsite-box 54)
    - Castaigne Drawings, 1904 (Offsite-box 54)
    - Charleston Public Library (Charleston, NC), 1924-1925 (Offsite-box 54)
    - Chase Manufacturing Company Offices (Waterbury, CT) (Box 1 of 8), 1916-1932 (Offsite-box 54)
    - Chase Manufacturing Company Offices (Waterbury, CT) (Box 2 of 8), 1916-1932 (Offsite-box 55)
    - Chase Manufacturing Company Offices (Waterbury, CT) (Box 3 of 8), 1916-1932 (Offsite-box 56)
    - Chase Manufacturing Company Offices (Waterbury, CT) (Box 4 of 8), 1916-1932 (Offsite-box 57)
    - Chase Manufacturing Company Offices (Waterbury, CT) (Box 5 of 8), 1916-1932 (Offsite-box 58)
    - Chase Manufacturing Company Offices (Waterbury, CT) (Box 6 of 8), 1916-1932 (Offsite-box 59)
    - Chase Manufacturing Company Offices (Waterbury, CT) (Box 7 of 8), 1916-1932 (Offsite-box 60)
    - Chase Manufacturing Company Offices (Waterbury, CT) (Box 8 of 8), 1916-1932 (Offsite-box 61)
    - Chase Memorial Dispensary (Waterbury, CT) (Box 1 of 2), 1923-1924 (Offsite-box 61)
    - Chase Memorial Dispensary (Waterbury, CT) (Box 2 of 2), 1923-1924 (Offsite-box 62)
    - The Chronicle Company, 1901 (Offsite-box 62)
    - Cleveland, Ralph D., 1901 (Offsite-box 62)
    - Continental National Bank of Chicago (Chicago, IL), 1902 (Offsite-box 62)
    - Criterion Club Building Committee, 1903 (Offsite-box 62)
    - Day, Frank Miles, 1902-1905 (Offsite-box 62)
    - Dayton Avenue Presbyterian Church (St. Paul, MN), 1902-1912 (Offsite-box 62)
    - De Laittre, John (His residence), 1905 (Offsite-box 63)
    - Delmonico Site Hotel Project (Broadway, 5th Avenue and 26th Street, NY, NY), 1900-1901 (Offsite-box 63)
    - Detroit Public Library (Detroit, MI) (Box 1 of 13), 1913-1933 (Offsite-box 63)
    - Detroit Public Library (Detroit, MI) (Box 2 of 13), 1913-1933 (Offsite-box 64)
    - Detroit Public Library (Detroit, MI) (Box 3 of 13), 1913-1933 (Offsite-box 65)
    - Detroit Public Library (Detroit, MI) (Box 4 of 13), 1913-1933 (Offsite-box 66)
    - Detroit Public Library (Detroit, MI) (Box 5 of 13), 1913-1933 (Offsite-box 67)
    - Detroit Public Library (Detroit, MI) (Box 6 of 13), 1913-1933 (Offsite-box 68)
    - Detroit Public Library (Detroit, MI) (Box 7 of 13), 1913-1933 (Offsite-box 69)
    - Detroit Public Library (Detroit, MI) (Box 8 of 13), 1913-1933 (Offsite-box 70)
    - Detroit Public Library (Detroit, MI) (Box 9 of 13), 1913-1933 (Offsite-box 71)
    - Detroit Public Library (Detroit, MI) (Box 10 of 13), 1913-1933 (Offsite-box 72)
    - Detroit Public Library (Detroit, MI) (Box 11 of 13), 1913-1933 (Offsite-box 73)
    - Detroit Public Library (Detroit, MI) (Box 12 of 13), 1913-1933 (Offsite-box 74)
    - Detroit Public Library (Detroit, MI) (Box 13 of 13), 1913-1933 (Offsite-box 75)
    - Elwere, Edwin (Curator of Sculpture, Metropolitan Museum of Art), 1902 (Offsite-box 75)
    - Endicott Building (St. Paul, MN) (Box 1 of 2), 1901-1916 (Offsite-box 75)
    - Endicott Building (St. Paul, MN) (Box 2 of 2), 1901-1916 (Offsite-box 76)
    - Endicott Building -Rantoul portion (St. Paul, MN), 1902 (Offsite-box 76)
    - Essex Building (St. Paul), 1905-1906 (Offsite-box 76)
    - Essex Country Courthouse (Newark, NJ) (Box 1 of 16), 1901-1929 (Offsite-box 76)
    - Essex Country Courthouse (Newark, NJ) (Box 2 of 16), 1901-1929 (Offsite-box 77)
    - Essex Country Courthouse (Newark, NJ) (Box 3 of 16), 1901-1929 (Offsite-box 78)
    - Essex Country Courthouse (Newark, NJ) (Box 4 of 16), 1901-1929 (Offsite-box 79)
    - Essex Country Courthouse (Newark, NJ) (Box 5 of 16), 1901-1929 (Offsite-box 80)
    - Essex Country Courthouse (Newark, NJ) (Box 6 of 16), 1901-1929 (Offsite-box 81)
    - Essex Country Courthouse (Newark, NJ) (Box 7 of 16), 1901-1929 (Offsite-box 82)
    - Essex Country Courthouse (Newark, NJ) (Box 8 of 16), 1901-1929 (Offsite-box 83)
    - Essex Country Courthouse (Newark, NJ) (Box 9 of 16), 1901-1929 (Offsite-box 84)
    - Essex Country Courthouse (Newark, NJ) (Box 10 of 16), 1901-1929 (Offsite-box 85)
    - Essex Country Courthouse (Newark, NJ) (Box 11 of 16), 1901-1929 (Offsite-box 86)
    - Essex Country Courthouse (Newark, NJ) (Box 12 of 16), 1901-1929 (Offsite-box 87)
    - Essex Country Courthouse (Newark, NJ) (Box 13 of 16), 1901-1929 (Offsite-box 88)
    - Essex Country Courthouse (Newark, NJ) (Box 14 of 16), 1901-1929 (Offsite-box 89)
    - Essex Country Courthouse (Newark, NJ) (Box 15 of 16), 1901-1929 (Offsite-box 90)
    - Essex Country Courthouse (Newark, NJ) (Box 16 of 16), 1901-1929 (Offsite-box 91)
    - Federal Reserve Bank of Minneapolis (Minneapolis, MN) (Box 1 of 18), 1919-1928 (Offsite-box 92)
    - Federal Reserve Bank of Minneapolis (Minneapolis, MN) (Box 2 of 18), 1919-1928 (Offsite-box 93)
    - Federal Reserve Bank of Minneapolis (Minneapolis, MN) (Box 3 of 18), 1919-1928 (Offsite-box 94)
    - Federal Reserve Bank of Minneapolis (Minneapolis, MN) (Box 4 of 18), 1919-1928 (Offsite-box 95)
    - Federal Reserve Bank of Minneapolis (Minneapolis, MN) (Box 5 of 18), 1919-1928 (Offsite-box 96)
    - Federal Reserve Bank of Minneapolis (Minneapolis, MN) (Box 6 of 18), 1919-1928 (Offsite-box 97)
    - Federal Reserve Bank of Minneapolis (Minneapolis, MN) (Box 7 of 18), 1919-1928 (Offsite-box 98)
    - Federal Reserve Bank of Minneapolis (Minneapolis, MN) (Box 8 of 18), 1919-1928 (Offsite-box 99)
    - Federal Reserve Bank of Minneapolis (Minneapolis, MN) (Box 9 of 18), 1919-1928 (Offsite-box 100)
    - Federal Reserve Bank of Minneapolis (Minneapolis, MN) (Box 10 of 18), 1919-1928 (Offsite-box 101)
    - Federal Reserve Bank of Minneapolis (Minneapolis, MN) (Box 11 of 18), 1919-1928 (Offsite-box 102)
    - Federal Reserve Bank of Minneapolis (Minneapolis, MN) (Box 12 of 18), 1919-1928 (Offsite-box 103)
    - Federal Reserve Bank of Minneapolis (Minneapolis, MN) (Box 13 of 18), 1919-1928 (Offsite-box 104)
    - Federal Reserve Bank of Minneapolis (Minneapolis, MN) (Box 14 of 18), 1919-1928 (Offsite-box 105)
    - Federal Reserve Bank of Minneapolis (Minneapolis, MN) (Box 15 of 18), 1919-1928 (Offsite-box 106)
    - Federal Reserve Bank of Minneapolis (Minneapolis, MN) (Box 16 of 18), 1919-1928 (Offsite-box 107)
    - Federal Reserve Bank of Minneapolis (Minneapolis, MN) (Box 17 of 18), 1919-1928 (Offsite-box 108)
    - Federal Reserve Bank of Minneapolis (Minneapolis, MN) (Box 18 of 18), 1919-1928 (Offsite-box 109)
    - 15-17 East 40th Street (New York, NY), 1916-1917 (Offsite-box 109)
    - Fifth Avenue and 72nd Street Apartment (New York, NY), 1911 (Offsite-box 109)
    - First Division Memorial (Washington, D.C) (Box 1 of 3), 1921-1934 (Offsite-box 110)
    - First Division Memorial (Washington, D.C) (Box 2 of 3), 1921-1934 (Offsite-box 111)
    - First Division Memorial (Washington, D.C) (Box 3 of 3), 1921-1934 (Offsite-box 112)
    - Floranada Club (Palm Beach, Florida), 1925-1934 (Offsite-box 113)
    - G. Fox and Co. Department Store (Hartford, CT) (Box 1 of 2), 1917-1932 (Offsite-box 113)
    - G. Fox and Co. Department Store (Hartford, CT) (Box 2 of 2), 1917-1932 (Offsite-box 114)
    - George Junior Republic School (Litchfield, CT), 1915-1917 (Offsite-box 114)
    - Grace Graves Memory Tablet (Duluth, MN), 1904-1905 (Offsite-box 114)
    - George Washington Bridge (see Hudson River Bridge)
    - Grand Island Bridge (see Niagara Frontier Bridge)
    - John L. Hamilton & Sons, 1902 (Offsite-box 114)
    - Helena Hotel (Helena, MT), 1912-1915 (Offsite-box 114)
    - Hodges and Nichols Building (Duluth, MN) (Box 1 of 2), 1900-1904 (Offsite-box 115)
    - Hodges and Nichols Building (Duluth, MN) (Box 2 of 2), 1900-1904 (Offsite-box 116)
    - Hotchkiss School (Lakeville, CT) (Box 1 of 11), 1914-1930 (Offsite-box 116)
    - Hotchkiss School (Lakeville, CT) (Box 2 of 11), 1914-1930 (Offsite-box 117)
    - Hotchkiss School (Lakeville, CT) (Box 3 of 11), 1914-1930 (Offsite-box 118)
    - Hotchkiss School (Lakeville, CT) (Box 4 of 11), 1914-1930 (Offsite-box 119)
    - Hotchkiss School (Lakeville, CT) (Box 5 of 11), 1914-1930 (Offsite-box 120)
    - Hotchkiss School (Lakeville, CT) (Box 6 of 11), 1914-1930 (Offsite-box 121)
    - Hotchkiss School (Lakeville, CT) (Box 7 of 11), 1914-1930 (Offsite-box 122)
    - Hotchkiss School (Lakeville, CT) (Box 8 of 11), 1914-1930 (Offsite-box 123)
    - Hotchkiss School (Lakeville, CT) (Box 9 of 11), 1914-1930 (Offsite-box 124)
    - Hotchkiss School (Lakeville, CT) (Box 10 of 11), 1914-1930 (Offsite-box 125)
    - Hotchkiss School (Lakeville, CT) (Box 11 of 11), 1914-1930 (Offsite-box 126)